(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-30T18:02:13.603119",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Love me more! Look at me more!
音返しは
My repayment is...
愛のこめた投げキスで
a kiss full of love!
企みのない目で見つめてよ
Look at me with honest eyes!
ハート作って 恋しちゃってください
Make a heart and fall in love with me!
やれること なんでもします
I'll do whatever it takes!
NGなしで体当たり挑戦
Giving it my all with no restrictions!
エゴサで見つけたアンチのコメ
Finding hater comments while self-searching,
ふざけんな 誰より分かってるし
don't mess with me, I know better!
でも大丈夫 どこにたってばみんながいる
But it's okay, wherever I am, everyone is here!
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Love me more! Look at me more!
音返しは
My repayment is...
愛のこめた投げキスで トリコにする
a kiss full of love to make you mine!
もっと夢を見せる もっと楽しむんで
Showing you more dreams, having more fun!
愛のこめたスペシャルナイト
A special night filled with love,
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'm gonna fan-service you!
お手紙も書いてください
Please write me letters too!
何度も読んで宝物にします
I'll read them over and make them my treasure.
スキャンダル まだ早いけど
Scandals are still way too early,
裏切りません 宣言しときます
but I promise I'll never betray you!
嫉妬嫌がらせには負けない ふざけんな実力で勝ってやる
I won't lose to jealousy or hate! I'll win with my real skills!
だからやめない 負けず嫌い 私はいる
That's why I won't stop, I hate losing, and I'm right here!
好きになって！もっと！私を見て！もっと！
Love me more! Look at me more!
音返しは
My repayment is...
愛のこめた祭りのもあビームで 大感せい
a Matsuri-more beam full of love—great cheers!
もっとまだまだねえもっと受け止めてね
More, still more, hey, accept it more!
愛のこめたわがままソング
A selfish song filled with love!
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'm gonna fan-service you!
次も 次も また会えるよね
We'll meet again and again, right?
約束！
It's a promise!
祭りす！
Matsuris!
誕生日 今年も祝ってくれてありがとう
Thank you for celebrating my birthday again this year!
優しいさに溢れている言葉も
Even words overflowing with kindness,
心ない誰かの言葉さえも 必要なんだ 強くなろう
and heartless words from someone... I need them to grow stronger.
月に叫べ もっと楽しんじゃえ
Shout at the moon, have even more fun!
忘れまいで 特別な日になりますように
Please don't forget, so today becomes a special day!
共に歌おう 共に歩もう ずっと
Let's sing together, let's walk together forever!
合言葉はとびっきりのL･O･V･E!
Our watchword is a super special L-O-V-E!
好きになって！もっと！
Love me more! More!
祭りを見て！もっと！
Look at Matsuri! More!
恩返しは“愛の込めた投げキスで”
I'll return the favor with a love-filled flying kiss!
虜にする！もっと！
Captivating you! More!
夢を見せる！もっと！
Showing you dreams! More!
楽しんでって愛の込めたスペシャルナイト ファンサしちゃうぞ
Enjoy this special night full of love, I'll fan-service you!
ファンサしちゃうぞ
I'll fan-service you!
はい、ということで早速聞いていただきました、ファンサでした！ありがとうございました！
So, with that, you just heard "Fansa"! Thank you very much!
はあ、ちょっと1曲目から歌って踊って息が上がっておりますけども、
Phew, having sung and danced right from the first song, I'm a bit out of breath!
ということで改めて、え、祭りすの皆さん、見てるかー？
So once again, hey, Matsuris, are you watching?
今日は祭りちゃんのお誕生日だー！わーい！お祝いに来てくれてありがとうございます！なんと、
Today is Matsuri-chan's birthday! Yay! Thank you so much for coming to celebrate! And guess what,
え、デビューしてから4回目の誕生日を迎えたらしいですよ！4回だよ！すごくない？
apparently, this is my 4th birthday since my debut! Fourth time! Isn't that amazing?
すごいでございますね。いや、そんな中でね、1回目の誕生日は、あの、YouTubeの収益化がまだ通ってなくて、ツイキャスでやってたりとか。2回目は、ツイキャスでやったっけ？っていうレベルなんですよ。
That's incredible. Well, for my first birthday, YouTube monetization hadn't gone through yet, so I did it on TwitCasting. The second time, was it on TwitCasting? That's the level it was at.
なのでね、こうやって4回もね、みんなと誕生日を過ごすことができて、初めての方もね、2回目の方とかもいるかもしれないんですけども、本当に嬉しいなと思っております。
And so, being able to spend my birthday with everyone for the 4th time like this—there might be some here for the first time or the second time—I'm truly so happy about it.
そして、今回はね、ちょっと特別なものが色々あるので、見ていただきたい！まずは、ちょっと背景にも映ってるんですけど、
And this time, there are various special things, so I want you to check them out! First, well, it's reflected in the background too,
こちら、どどーん！見える？これさ、これこれ！このスピーカーでございますよ！
right here, ta-da! Can you see? Look at this, look at this! These are speakers!
はい。これね、祭りの髪飾りのスナギモっていうね、にゃんこがいるんですけど、そのにゃんこのスピーカー、そしてひまわり。祭りといえばひまわりみたいなとこありますからね。
Yes. These have "Sunagimo," Matsuri's hair ornament cat—there's a cat speaker—and sunflowers. Speaking of Matsuri, it's kind of like sunflowers, right?
ひまわりのスピーカーを作っていただきました！ありがとう運営さん！ありがとうございます！超かわいいでしょ？
They made sunflower speakers for me! Thank you, management! Thank you so much! Super cute, right?
そしてそしてね、まだあるんです。もう見えてると思うんですけども、こちらじゃん！マイク！祭りのオリジナルのマイクでございます！
And, and, there's more. I think you can already see it, but here, ta-da! The microphone! This is Matsuri's original microphone!
超かわいくない？見える？リボン付いてて、ほら、ここ後ろにもスナギモもついてるんですよ。
Isn't it super cute? Can you see? It has a ribbon, and look, Sunagimo is on the back here too.
そう。で、バーチャルならではの、なんか何て言うの、ホログラム？言うんですか？がもんもんもんって周りに付いているわけでございますよ。
Yeah. And, like, unique to a virtual world, what do you call it, a hologram? Is that what you say? It's all around me, glowing and stuff.
これもね、もういつから、半年前からかから全部ね、あの、運営さんと相談したからね、どうしてもやりたいのでお願いしますって言って進めてきたのでね、今日お披露目できてよかったなと思います。
This too, starting from half a year ago, I consulted with management saying "I really want to do this, please," and we proceeded with it, so I'm really glad I could unveil it today.
ということで、ええ、もう次の曲に行きたいと思うんですけども、まあ、まあ祭りはね、あの、好きな曲を今日、好きな人のために、そう、祭りすのために、歌いたいと思って来たので、
And with that, um, I want to move on to the next song, but well, Matsuri wanted to sing today's favorite song for the people she loves, yes, for Matsuris,
ま、その中でも、ま、カバーになってしまうんですが、あの、あれですね、祭りが一番好きなHoneyWorksさんの曲をここから2曲続けて歌わせていただきたいと思います！
so among that, although it ends up being a cover, um, I'd like to sing two consecutive songs starting from here, which are HoneyWorks songs that Matsuri loves the most!
ということで、緊張する。それでは聞いてください、ナンバーワン！
With that being said, I'm so nervous. Well then, please listen, Number One!
ごめん
I'm sorry,
憧れてた
I admired you,
追いかけてた
I chased after you.
いつまでもそう でいたかった
I wanted to stay like that forever.
完璧な あなた
The perfect you
嫌いになった
I grew to dislike.
同じように愛ももらって育ったのに
Even though we were raised with the same love,
いつからか差が開いていた
before I knew it, the gap had widened.
やっと当たり前ってしたかった
I just wanted to take it for granted.
ねぇ maybe
Hey, maybe
神様は試練与えた
God gave me a trial,
強く なれと
telling me to be strong.
ウザい平等なんて嘘つき
"So annoying!" Equality is such a lie.
わかってる けど
I already knew that, but...
可愛いとかモテたいとか
Wanting to be cute or popular,
諦めないの女の子だし
I'm a girl who doesn't give up!
上品らしく(ハイっ)
Gently (Hi!)
猫かぶり(ニャンっ)
Feigning innocence (Nya!)
オンリーワンだよ☆愛してね
I'm the one and only!☆ Make sure to love me,
生き方は無限にある
There are infinite ways to live,
お父さんの大げさな言葉
those were my dad's exaggerated words.
私らしくいこう
Let's go with my own style,
暇じゃない人生生きよう
and live a busy life without leisure.
だって理想言えばキリがなくて
Because if we talk ideals, there's no end,
無いもの全部欲しがって
wanting everything that I don't have.
鏡を睨んでため息はぁ
Looking in the mirror, I let out a sigh,
あなただって悩んでいた
I never knew that you were troubled too,
知らなかったみんなと同じだと知った
and that you were just like everyone else.
ピンと張った糸緩んでく
The tightly strung thread has loosened up.
ねぇ maybe
Hey, maybe
神様は楽しんでる
God is having fun
予測できない人を
with unpredictable people.
私はそれ以上に楽しんでやるぜ
I'll have even more fun than that!
勉強とかお仕事とか
Studying or working,
諦めないの女の子だし
I'm a girl who doesn't give up!
元気よく(ハイっ)
Energetically (Hi!)
愛想よく(ニャンっ)
Sociably (Nya!)
たまにはクールについてきて
Sometimes acting cool, follow me!
愛した分愛されるのお母さんがくれたアドバイス
Loving in return for being loved, that was mom's advice.
張り切って(ハイっ)ミスしても(ニャンっ)
Enthusiastically (Hi!) Even if I make mistakes (Nya!)
私らしくいこう
Let's go with my own style,
胸張って生きる
and live proudly.
さらけ出せば心が叩かれてたんだ
If I bare it all, my heart was tested.
好きに言わせてろ痛くない
"Say whatever you want," it doesn't hurt.
神様は夢与えた
God gave me a dream
変われるために
in order for me to change.
サンキューのっかってやるよ
"Thank you!" I'll ride along with it,
最後まで付き合って貰うよ
and have you stay with me until the end.
雨はヤンで傘を閉じた
The rain stopped, I closed my umbrella.
今まで見えてなかった景色
Scenery I'd never seen before
透明が反射して世界を照らした
transparent reflections illuminated the world.
胸躍る
My heart is pounding!
可愛いとかモテたいとか
Wanting to be cute or popular,
諦めないの女の子だし
I'm a girl who doesn't give up!
上品らしく(ハイっ)
Gently (Hi!)
猫かぶり(ニャンっ)
Feigning innocence (Nya!)
ナンバーワンでしょ☆愛してね
I'm number one, right?☆ Love me,
生き方は無限にある
there are infinite ways to live.
ピンクとか後ろ髪とか
Pink or holding back,
諦めないの女の子だし
I'm a girl who doesn't give up!
元気よく(ハイっ)愛想よく(ニャンっ)
Energetically (Hi!) Sociably (Nya!)
たまにはクールについてきて
Sometimes acting cool, follow me!
愛した分愛されるのお母さんがくれたアドバイス
Loving in return for being loved, mom's advice.
張り切って(ハイっ)ミスしても(ニャンっ)
Enthusiastically (Hi!) Even if I make mistakes (Nya!)
私らしくいこう
Let's go with my own style,
胸張って生きる
and live proudly.
さらけ出せば心が叩かれてたんだ
If I bare it all, my heart was tested.
好きに言わせてろ痛くない
"Say whatever you want," it doesn't hurt.
神様は夢与えた
God gave me a dream
変われるために
in order for me to change.
サンキューのっかってやるよ
"Thank you!" I'll ride along with it,
最後まで付き合って貰うよ
and have you stay with me until the end.
雨はヤンで傘を閉じた
The rain stopped, I closed my umbrella.
今まで見えてなかった景色
Scenery I'd never seen before.
さらけ出せば 心が温められてたんだ
If I bare it all, my heart was warmed.
好きに言ってろ 痛くない
"Say whatever you want," it doesn't hurt.
神様は夢与えた
God gave me a dream
変われるために
in order for me to change.
サンキューのっかってやるよ
"Thank you!" I'll ride along with it,
最後まで付き合って貰うよ
and have you stay with me until the end.
雨はヤンで傘を閉じた
The rain stopped, I closed my umbrella.
今まで見えてなかった景色
Scenery I'd never seen before
透明が反射して世界を照らした
transparent reflections illuminated the world.
胸躍る
My heart is pounding!
可愛いとかモテたいとか
Wanting to be cute or popular,
諦めないの女の子だし
I'm a girl who doesn't give up!
上品らしく(ハイっ)
Gently (Hi!)
猫かぶり(ニャンっ)
Feigning innocence (Nya!)
ナンバーワンでしょ☆愛してね
I'm number one, right?☆ Love me,
可愛いとかモテたいとか
Wanting to be cute or popular,
諦めないの女の子だし
I'm a girl who doesn't give up!
上品らしく(ハイっ)
Gently (Hi!)
猫かぶり(ニャンっ)
Feigning innocence (Nya!)
ナンバーワンでしょ☆愛してね
I'm number one, right?☆ Love me,
生き方は無限にある
there are infinite ways to live,
お父さんの大げさな言葉
those were dad's exaggerated words.
愛してね生き方は
Love me, ways to live
無限にあるお父さんの
are infinite, dad's
大げさな言葉は上品らしく猫かぶり
exaggerated words: gently feigning innocence,
祭りらしくいこう
let's go Matsuri-style!
暇じゃない人生生きよう
Let's live a busy life without leisure,
息を切らし
running out of breath,
猫かぶり
feigning innocence,
祭りらしくいこう
let's go Matsuri-style!
暇じゃない人生生きよう
Let's live a busy life without leisure,
運命
destiny...
生きよう
Let's live on.
可愛くね とびきりの愛よ届け！
So cute! Sending you my ultimate love!
よろしければ名前だけでも覚えてってください
If you don't mind, please remember my name!
レッスン開始！意気込むけれど
Lesson start! I'm all pumped up, but...
歌って踊ってヘトヘト
Singing and dancing leaves me exhausted.
比較されることもあるけど
Sometimes I get compared to others,
私は私でありがたい
but I'm grateful to just be myself.
本気出さなきゃ響かないんだ
If I don't give my all, it won't resonate.
ファンの心を掴みたいんだ
I want to capture my fans' hearts.
だからスタート全開飛ばしますよ
That's why I'm going full speed ahead!
可愛くね とびきりの愛よ届け！
So cute! Sending you my ultimate love!
よろしければ名前だけでも覚えてってください
If you don't mind, please remember my name!
あざとくね とびきりのスマイルで
So coy! With a dazzling smile,
よろしければ「推し」にしちゃってくれませんか？
Won't you make me your favorite?
なんてね！笑
Just kidding!
ちょっぴりマジなの期待していいですか？
Can I hope you're a little serious?
人生変えるそんな一日
A single day that changes my life,
憧れ夢見たステージ
The stage I've always dreamed of.
オシャレ？流行り？追いつけなくて
Fashionable? Trendy? I can't keep up,
言い訳弱音も出ちゃうよ
so excuses and complaints slip out.
愛想悪いし こんなアイドル他にいないし
I'm unfriendly, and no other idol is like me.
でもね絶対絶対見返すんだ
But I will definitely prove them wrong!
愛してね「日本一」夢見てる
Love me! Dreaming of being #1 in Japan.
よろしければ合いの手一つ入れてやってください
If you don't mind, please join the call!
手を上げて視線独り占めして！
Raise your hands and hog all my attention!
よろしければ愛を恵んでくれませんか？
Won't you bestow your love upon me?
なんてね！
Just kidding!
絶対後悔させませんよマジでね！
I seriously won't let you regret it!
今もステージは胸がギュッと熱くなる
This stage still makes my heart race.
やれる景色焼き付けて歌う声に愛を込める
I pour love into my singing voice.
響く歓声気持ち高鳴る
Cheers echo, making my heart race.
これは証明私ここだよ
This is proof that I'm right here!
いくよ！絶対絶対声出してね！
Here we go! Shout out loud!
可愛くね とびきりの愛よ届け！
So cute! Sending you my ultimate love!
よろしければ名前だけでも覚えてってください
If you don't mind, please remember my name!
あざとくね とびきりのスマイルで
So coy! With a dazzling smile,
よろしければ「推し」にしちゃってくれませんか？
Won't you make me your favorite?
なんてね！笑
Just kidding!
ちょっぴりマジなの期待していいですか？
Can I hope you're a little serious?
はーい、ということでありがとうございましたー！
Alright, thank you very much!
え、ちょっとね、あの、連続で歌ったんで、ちょっと使えてしまったんで、MCをね、挟みたいと思いますよ。
Since I sang back-to-back, I'm worn out,
いやね、可愛いステージに可愛いマイクにね、本当にさっきも、あの、紹介したんですけど、嬉しいね！
With this cute stage and mic,
でも！……実、は、まだまだね、見せてないものがあるんですよ。なので、ちょっと見せちゃおうかな？
But!... Actually, there's more.
それでは、いきますよー！チェンジ！
Well then, here we go! Change!
ねぇ、おっ？
Hey, oh?
おおっ！？
Whoa!?
と言うことで、なんとかイヤホンマイクって言うんですか？
So, they call these earphone mics,
こう耳につける感じのね、可愛らしいのが……あるでしょ、ないですか？
the cute ones that attach to your ears... Aren't there? Right?
可愛いね、可愛いね。
So cute, so cute.
と言うことで、この後の曲は、ちょっとマイク、手持ちマイクじゃなくてこちらのマイクを使って行きたいと思います！
So, for the next song, instead of a handheld microphone, I'd like to use this microphone!
あー、ナイス！
Ah, nice!
いや、今年はね、結構いろんなことがありまして、3周年でね、
Well, this year, quite a lot has happened. With our 3rd anniversary,
あのー、1期生とね、ライブをやったりとかもしたんですけど、あれからも1ヶ月半経ってるらしいですよ。
um, we did a live with the 1st gen, and it's apparently been a month and a half since then.
もうね、早いね時の流れって。もう誕生日だなあって思って、
Time flies so fast. I thought it was my birthday already,
すぐね4周年が来てしまうんじゃないかっていう感じなんですけども。
and it feels like the 4th anniversary will be here in no time.
まあ、今年、そして来年は、新しいことに挑戦しつつも、ま、安定期というか、
Well, this year and next year, while taking on new challenges, I hope to maintain a stable period—
あのー、楽しく、ゆるく、長く続けられるようにできたらいいなと思っておりますのでね、
enjoyable, relaxed, and long-lasting—so I hope we can keep going. Please support me.
あのー、よろしくお願いします。
Thank you for your continued support.
来年の誕生日もぜひね、祝ってくださいよ。
Please be sure to celebrate my birthday next year too!
ということで、続いての曲なんですけども、次はソロじゃなくて、なんか誰か来る気がするんですよーね。いや来ないかなー？来ないかなー？来るかなー？
With that said, for the next song, it's not a solo, but I have a feeling someone's coming... Will they come? Won't they? Will they?
来た！
They're here!
1期生が来てくれたぞー！やったー！1期生が来てくれたぞー！来ちゃったよ！なんか来た！
1st gen is here! Yay! 1st gen is here! They're here! Someone came!
あれ？薄っぺらいのがいますけど。昨日、昨日のせいかな？昨日せいかな？
Huh? There's a flat one here. Is it because of yesterday? Yesterday's fault?
ちょっと、横向いてもらってもいいですか？あ、横
Um, could you turn sideways? Ah, sideways—
ま、ピロチャマが！ピロチャマが！ピロチャマが！
Ah, Pirochama! Pirochama! Pirochama!
来てくれましたね。はい。ピロチャマ、わーい！
She came. Yes. Pirochama, yay!
と言うことで、今回はね、1期生のみんなが集まってくれたのでね、はい！祭りを祝って欲しいなと思うところではございますのですけども、
So, since all the 1st gen members gathered this time, I want them to celebrate Matsuri! But...
ちょっと、誕生日だしプレゼントとして祭りの願い1個ずつ聞いて貰いたいなと思って。いいですか？なんだろう？いいですか？なんだ？
since it's my birthday, as a present, I want to have each of you grant one of Matsuri's wishes. Is that okay? What could it be?
じゃあ、ちょっとあの、カメラさんがいると思うのでこちらのね。はい。あの、1人ずつじゃ、アキロゼからちょっと近づいてもらって
Well, since the camera is over there, one by one... Akirose, come a little closer.
何させられるんだろう？
What am I going to be made to do?
あのー、祭りに、祭りちゃん好きだよっていう一言を、ちょっとこれ永久保存版にしたいので
Um, I want to make a permanent record of you saying 'I love you, Matsuri-chan' to Matsuri,
ぜひ、ちょっとあの、VTuberとかも全部ないこの状況でお願いします。
so please do it in this situation where even VTuber stuff isn't available.
それでは、ちょっとアキロゼの告白まで
Well then, until Akirose's confession...
3、2、1、キュッ！
3, 2, 1, cue!
まつりちゃん、大好きだよ。
Matsuri-chan, I love you so much.
あらあら、あらあら……。続いては、あらあらとか言ってる白上さん。白上さん？白上さんは何を？
My, my... Next is Shirakami-san saying 'my, my.' Shirakami-san? What about you, Shirakami-san?
わーまあ、あの、祭りの嫁宣言をちょっとしてもらおうかなと。
Well, I'd like you to declare yourself as Matsuri's wife.
私、白上フブキは、祭りちゃんの嫁です！っておねがいしていいですか？嫁でいいんですか？
Could you say, 'I, Shirakami Fubuki, am Matsuri-chan's wife'? Is wife okay?
好感度が上がってる！
Her favorability is going up!
それでは白上さんの嫁宣言まで、3、2、1、キュッ！
Well then, until Shirakami-san's wife declaration, 3, 2, 1, cue!
白上フブキは、えー、本日より
Shirakami Fubuki, um, as of today,
いやー、デビューしてからはどうかと思いますけども、改めてまして、祭りちゃんの、いや嫁であるということをここに申請させていただきます！イェーイ！
Well, I think since debut... but once again, I hereby apply that I am Matsuri-chan's wife! Yay!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
何嫁が言いんだよ！何嫁が言いんだときめこう！
What kind of wife is that! Make my heart flutter!
シッテルシクショウ！いいプレゼントだなあ！
I know right, dammit! What a great present!
それでは最後はメル！メルには何をさせる気？
And finally, Mel! What are you going to make Mel do?
メルメルは、いつも、いつも、メルがカップカップする方だけど、今日は祭りちゃんにカップカップされたいなあって
Mel-mel is usually the one who does the 'cup cup' (cooing/headpats), but today I want Matsuri-chan to 'cup cup' me,
てれ、照れ顔でね、照れ照れしながら言ってもらおうかな。いいかな？
with a bashful, embarrassed face, saying it. Is that okay?
あの、色気ある感じでお願いします。色気ある感じ？それではメルのそんなセリフまで
Um, please do it with a sexy vibe. A sexy vibe? Well then, until Mel's such line...
3、2、1、キュッ！
3, 2, 1, cue!
まつりちゃん、いつもメルがカップカップする側だけど、今日はまつりちゃんにカップカップされたいな……。
Matsuri-chan, I'm usually the one who 'cup cups' you, but today, I want to be 'cup cupped' by Matsuri-chan...
集まったっていうことは、
Since everyone is gathered here...
やっぱり、あの曲を歌わないと始まらないですよね？
We definitely have to start by singing that song, right?
なんだ？
What?
え、なんだ？なんだ？なんだじゃない
Huh? What? What do you mean "what"?
あれだね、あれ。あれしかなくない？わかんない。
That thing, right? Isn't it only that? I don't know.
あれじゃ…
So...
あれ、大丈夫？あれ、大丈夫？
Huh? Is that okay? Is that okay?
もちろん、もちろん！
Of course, of course!
それでは、いくよ！ミュージック、スタート！
Well then, let's go! Music, start!
輝くよ 季節駆け巡って
Shining as we race through the seasons,
春風 君を乗せて 夏色が迎えるよ
Spring breeze carrying you, Natsuiro welcomes you!
色めく秋が背中を押したら
When vibrant autumn gives you a push on the back,
真っ赤っ赤 吹雪 きらめく 巡り巡るハート
Bright red, Blizzard, sparkling, a revolving heart!
なにも分からない 一歩進んで
Not knowing anything, taking a step forward,
やっとここまでたどり着けたね
we finally made it here.
街はビターズ＆スウィート
The city is bittersweet,
素敵なステージ 一番に見せてあげるよ
a wonderful stage, I'll show it to you first!
行こう！スマイル、スマイル！Catch out！
Let's go! Smile, smile! Catch out!
ヒューチャームジカに巡る季節が世界をかけて巡って
Futuristic music as the revolving seasons race across the world
夢のような君へと 行こう！
toward a dreamlike you, let's go!
ライト、ライト、ライト！On futuristic
Light, light, light! On futuristic,
僕らが一緒とさ
let's be together and
照らし続けよう
keep shining!
スポットライトはついたばかり
The spotlight has just turned on,
輝くここだけのイルミネーション
The illumination sparkling right here,
心は色とりどり 弾け飛ぶすれ違う しあわせいっぱい
hearts are colorful, bursting and passing by, full of happiness!
注ごうローズグラス 鳴らしてキラッと冷めるよ
Pouring into rose glasses, ringing with a sparkling chill—
何事もないような気持ち 十時の鐘だんな 忘れちゃって
feelings like nothing's wrong, forgetting the 10 o'clock bell...
ずっと解けない魔法をかけよう ときめきがして
Let's cast a spell that never wears off, making my heart flutter,
そっと胸踊る時間を贈るから 絶対ついておいでよ
gently sending you a time that makes your heart dance, definitely come along!
行こう！ポップ、ポップ、ポップ！Catch out！
Let's go! Pop, pop, pop! Catch out!
ヒューチャー色をかけるいつつ星世界を巻き込んで賑やかに遊ぼう
Futuristic colors casting a five-star world, let's get entangled and play lively!
ずっと、ファスト、ファスト、メイカーアップ、ヒューチャー 目もくらむステージ まだ踊り足りないでしょ
Fast, fast, making up, futuristic, a dazzling stage—aren't you still unsatisfied with dancing?
カーテンコールはずっとずっと先まで
The curtain call is far, far ahead!
楽しむ気持ちさえ持って来たら きっと誰もが主役になれるよ
If you bring along a heart ready to have fun, surely anyone can become the star!
雨の日も曇りの日ももっと素敵で もっとじゃんじゃん
Rain or shine, let's be even more wonderful and lively!
たとえ退屈の世界も一緒に遊び尽くそう
Even in a boring world, let's play it to the fullest together!
響け、クラップ、クラップ、ネクストステージ このメロディが終わっても消して
Ring out, clap, clap, next stage—even when this melody ends, don't erase it,
今日だけの思い出にはしないよ
we won't let it be just a memory of today!
行こう！スマイル、スマイル！Catch out！
Let's go! Smile, smile! Catch out!
ヒューチャームジカに巡る傷つく世界を溶け込んで夢のような君へと
Futuristic music melting into the hurting world toward a dreamlike you,
逃げろ！ライト、ライト、ライト！On futuristic 僕らが一緒とさて、出し続けよう
Light, light, light! On futuristic, let's keep shining together!
スポットライトは終わらない
The spotlight will never end!
でいり〜だいあり〜！
Deiri~ daiari~!
届けちゃおう
Let's send it out!
せ〜しゅん実況中！（きらきら）
Live youth broadcasting! (Sparkling)
ちょ〜せん配信中！（試して）
Challenging live stream! (Try it)
せ〜しゅん実況中！（いっぱい）
Live youth broadcasting! (So much)
ほらね、楽しいわ
Look, it's so much fun!
また新しい『好き』が見つかったよ
I found a brand new favorite!
（何々? 超気になる!）
(What is it? I'm so curious!)
近所でできたカフェの『ケーキ』
なんかすごく美味しかったんだよ
The cake from the nearby café
was super delicious!
10連ガチャ引いてみよう（欲しい!）
Let's pull a 10-pull gacha! (I want it!)
ホラーゲームやってみよう（絶叫!）
Let's try a horror game! (Screaming!)
知らなかったゲームや（新作!）
聞いたことない歌（新曲!）
Games I didn't know (New release!)
Songs I've never heard (New song!)
ちょっと気になったら手をしちゃう
ほ・ら・ま・た
If something catches my eye, I reach out
Ho-ra-ma-ta
いっしょに遊ぼう！（配信!）
Let's play together! (Stream!)
窓の向こうの笑顔に手をしちゃう！
Reaching out to the smile beyond the window!
アニメ視聴中… 発見！
Watching anime... Discovered!
モブのキャラに推せるポテンシャル
Potential to stan a mob character
知名度ないマンガや（名作!）
思いついた新ネタ（爆笑）
Unknown manga (Masterpiece!)
New jokes I thought up (Bursting with laughter)
あたない天気予報もきっと
Even an unexpected weather forecast
面白いことなるんだよ（配信!）
Will surely turn out interesting! (Stream!)
聞いて！聞いて！今日の日！（なに?）
Listen! Listen! Today is! (What?)
目覚めなくちゃなくて
I had to wake up early
寝過ごしちゃったのは（どうして?）
Why did I oversleep? (Why?)
昨晩の生放送！
Last night's live broadcast!
すっごく楽しくて
寝付けなかったんだ！（ふぁわ〜ねむ）
It was so much fun
I couldn't fall asleep! (Yawn... sleepy)
特別すごいことなんて、そう起きない現実
だけど、そのエッセンス
Nothing extraordinarily amazing happens in reality,
but that essence
仮想の世界、夢に変えて
毎日がパラダイス！
Turns the virtual world into a dream,
Every day is paradise!
おもいっきり遊んで笑っちゃおう！
Let's play to our heart's content and laugh!
「対戦実況ー!」「いえーい!」
"Battle stream!" "Yeah!"
「全米を泣かす覚悟でてきた」「なにそれ〜?」
"I came prepared to make America cry" "What's that?"
「勝てる気がしないんだけど〜」
"I feel like I have no chance of winning~"
「諦めたら実況終了だよー?」
"If you give up, the stream ends, you know?"
「えー! まだ終わりたくないー!」
"Eh! I don't want it to end yet!"
どんな毎日も楽しくなっちゃうんだ
だって、いつでもほらあなたが待ってるの！
Every single day becomes so fun,
because look, you're always waiting!
みんなで毎日を（編集）
出会えた嬉しいを（実況）
Editing every day together,
Broadcasting our joy of meeting,
みんなと一緒に（共有）
気分はね、もう最高潮！
Sharing it with everyone together,
Our mood is already at its peak!
窓の向こうの笑顔に手を振って
配信でとどける our daily diary
Waveing to the smile beyond the window,
Delivering through our stream, our daily diary
でいり〜だいあり〜！
Deiri~ daiari~!
届けちゃおう
Let's send it out!
せ〜しゅん実況中！（きらきら）
Live youth broadcasting! (Sparkling)
ちょ〜せん配信中！（試して）
Challenging live stream! (Try it)
せ〜しゅん実況中！（いっぱい）
Live youth broadcasting! (So much)
ちょ〜せん配信中！（遊ぼう）
Challenging live stream! (Let's play)
でいり〜だいあり〜！
届けよう！
Deiri~ daiari~!
Let's deliver it!
楽しかったねー！
That was so fun!
本当にね！
It really was!
でもさ、ほらほら…
You know...
他のメンバーの曲って歌うことないじゃん？
We never usually sing other members' songs, right?
ない！確かに！
True! Exactly!
こういう機会でね！
On an occasion like this!
リクエストの多かった他のホロメンの曲もね…
We wanted you to hear other requested Holomember songs too...
聞いていただけたらなと思って新曲しました！
So we did a new version!
めちゃくちゃ楽しかったね！
It was super fun!
ということで、ここからはせっかくこのメンバーがいるんだから…
So, from here on, since we have all these members...
スクショタイムをして、みんなにツイートしてほしいなと！
Let's do a screenshot time and have everyone tweet!
ツイートしてね！
Be sure to tweet!
よーし、じゃあポーズを決めよっか！
Alright, let's decide on a pose!
星ちょっとみんなで作ろう、何でも。
Let's all make a star together, whatever kind.
ねえ、まっちゃん、ちょっと。10秒指から。
Hey, Matsuri, wait. From your 10 fingers.
はい。はーと！やったー！おめでとう！ありがとう！
Yes. Heart! Yay! Congratulations! Thank you!
嬉しい、嬉しい！最高のプレゼントだぜ。
I'm so happy! This is the best present.
続いてちょっと来てください。
Come over here next.
アメ目でやるね。はい。はーと！開いてる？
I'll do it with Ame. Yes. Heart! Is it open?
頑張れ、メル。頑張れ、オッケー！芯の力が。
Do your best, Mel. Do your best, okay! The core strength.
なってるね、なってる、なってる！ありがとう！
It's working, it's working! Thank you!
じゃあ最後に、よめ！よめ、おいで！
Now last, Fubuki! Fubuki, come here!
なんでそんな、お姉ちゃんって呼ばれるの？
Why do you call me big sis like that?
超えてやろうとしたら「ぐう」みたいな。オタクじゃん。
When I tried to surpass it, it went "guu". You're an otaku.
それ面白い、オタクの血！
That's funny, otaku blood!
あれ？おかしいな。オタクの血、おかしいな？嬉しいんだけど、誕生日だぞ、こっちは！
Huh? That's strange. Otaku blood, is that strange? I'm happy, it's my birthday, you know!
あ、やったー！やったー！これレアですね。
Ah, yay! Yay! This is rare.
やめやめ、ありがとー！イエーイ！
Stop, stop, thanks! Yay!
いや、嬉しい、嬉しい、嬉しいでございますよ。
Man, I'm so, so, so happy.
もう大丈夫か？他にないかい？画角距離でさ、なんかみんな写れないかな？
Are we good? Is there anyone else? Can we all fit in the frame distance?
あ、みんなアップで写れるのかな？しゅが、耳だけでもいいよ自分。
Ah, can everyone be in close-up? Sugar, even just your ears is fine.
なんで、なんで？
Why, why?
あー、もっともっと近づいてほしいし。
Ah, I want you to get closer and closer.
ねき、ねき。いいね、近い。しゃがまなくてもいいのか。
Neki, neki. Nice, close. You don't even have to crouch.
これ。いぇい！いぇい！いいな！こういうの、こういうのが撮りたかった。いや、良いですね。
This. Yay! Yay! Nice! This is the kind of thing I wanted to take. Yeah, it's good.
ちょっとハートちゃんさ、真ん中、ハートちゃん本当にに入れる？
Heart-chan, can you really fit in the middle?
いいよ、いいよ。
It's fine, it's fine.
じゃあ、ハートちゃんがこの辺で、でメルメルが…
Then Heart-chan around here, and Melmel...
メルメルちょっと前、前行って。メルメルちょっと前行って。はいはいはい。はい、これでも。
Melmel go a little forward. Melmel go a little forward. Yes yes yes. Okay, even with this.
しだ？しだ？ん？ここか？
Shida? Shida? Hmm? Here?
しだ？イエーイ！イエーイ！イエーイ！オッケーオッケー、撮れてる、撮れてる！撮れてる！イエーイ！ありがとー！
Shida? Yay! Yay! Yay! Okay okay, got it, got it! Got it! Yay! Thanks!
イエーイ！ということで、なかなかいいんじゃないですかね。
Yay! So, isn't this pretty good?
いいっすな。よいですね、よいですね。
That's nice. Very nice, very nice.
いや、満足しました。満足しました。
Man, I'm satisfied. I'm satisfied.
ということで、じゃあね、ちょっとまだまだ続いての曲もありますので、ちょっと待ってちょっとここから1人になるの不安だな。
So, well, there are still more songs coming up, so wait, I'm a bit nervous being by myself from here.
ああ、不安だからエンジンでも組んでさ、みんなの力が欲しいなー！しょうがないなー。やっちゃいましょう！
Ah, since I'm nervous, let's form a team huddle or something, I want everyone's energy! Oh well. Let's do it!
じゃあちょっとエンジン、いいよ。ひよってんの、まつり！ひよってん、ひよってん、ハッチラ、ハッチラ、ハッチラおいで！
Then let's do the engine, alright. Are you scared, Matsuri? Scared, scared, Hat-chira, Hat-chira, come here!
フブじゃん。ちょっとだけ声を。
It's Fubuki. Just give a voice a bit.
声声どうしよう。どんなのがいいかな？祭り早朝。
Voice, what should we do? What kind would be good? Matsuri early morning.
祭り早朝なん。何か。あっ！反対だね。ハト！ハト！違うんじゃない？反対じゃなかった。
Matsuri early morning. Something. Ah! It's the opposite. Haato! Haato! Isn't it wrong? It wasn't the opposite.
あ、ちょ、あ、あれ？ちょ、あ、ハトちゃん消えた！最終だけど、ちょ、まっ白になっちゃった。
Ah, wait, ah, huh? Wait, ah, Haato-chan disappeared! At the end, wait, she turned completely white.
嘘だろ？それじゃあ、何に？はい、じゃあ。
No way? Well then, what? Yes, then.
え、祭り、この後も頑張るし、来年のね、あの6月1日か2日かちょっと分からないですけど、またなんかみんなで集まって、4周年そして5周年も、あの、頑張って楽しく活動を続けていきましょう！
Um, Matsuri, I'll do my best after this too, and next year's, um, June 1st or 2nd, I'm not quite sure, but let's all get together again, and for the 4th anniversary and 5th anniversary too, um, let's work hard and happily continue our activities!
じゃあ、祭りか、祭りのことって言ったらみんなが愛してるぞって言って、あーしよ。
So, when Matsuri says "Matsuri's...", everyone will say "We love you!", and I'll do like this.
分かった。いくよ？はい。祭りのことー？愛してるぞー！
Understood. Ready? Yes. Matsuri-chan—? We love you!
ありがとう！いぇーい！頑張ってね、まつりちゃん！頑張れる、頑張れる、ありがとう！
Thank you! Yay! Good luck, Matsuri-chan! You can do it, you can do it, thank you!
それじゃあ、またお会いしましょう！見てるぞー！ありがとう！またね！いっしゅっしゅっしゅっしゅっしゅっしゅッ！
Well then, let's meet again! We're watching! Thank you! See you! Wooosh!
いやー、よかった！もう本当に、あれ？なんか異臭する時がしたけど（笑）。
Man, that was great! Really, huh? I felt like there was a strange smell for a moment (laughs).
いや、よかったー！やっぱあのメンバーがね、一番安心しますね。あれ？はーちゃん？はーちゃんは残りたいうの？あれ？消えた。というわけでね、どんどん続いての曲にまいりましょう！
Man, that was great! After all, that member gives me the most peace of mind. Huh? Ha-chan? Ha-chan wants to stay? Huh? Disappeared. And with that, let's move on to the next song!
もっともっと 上がるよ 空に
More and more, rising up to the sky
大きな夏の花
are large summer flowers.
君と眺める夏の花
The summer flowers I view with you
フーラフラ歩く香りに誘われて
Hoola-flah walking, lured by the scent,
遥か響く予感の音 どこまでも
Echoing far away, the sound of a premonition, wherever it goes—
キラキラ輝く祭りの 明かりに飛び込んで
Jumping into the sparkling, glowing lights of the festival—
ピカピカほおばる まっ赤ないちご飴
Munching happily on a shiny, bright red candied strawberry!
さあ、どーんとぱっとね、 ずっと待ってた
Now, with a loud bang and a flash, I've waited so long for this!
ほらね今年も 花火が打ち上がる
See? This year too, fireworks are being launched into the sky.
さあ祭だ祭だ祭だ わっしょい！
Come on, it's a festival, a festival, a festival, Wasshoi!
一人一人の声出して 手と手をつないで叫ぶよ わっしょい！
Everyone raising their voices, holding hands and shouting, Wasshoi!
まだまだ上がるよ 今夜の花火もテンションMAX！
The fireworks tonight will climb even higher, maxing out our tension!
ガヤガヤ賑わうもの 全てが眩しくて
Everything bustling and lively is so dazzling,
シャクシャク溶けかけ ほおばるかき氷
Crunching and melting away, a mouthful of shaved ice.
さあ、ばんぱかばかやって 服々笑わせて
Come on, let's do something silly and make everyone laugh,
君の笑顔の花火が打ち上がる
The fireworks of your smile launch into the sky!
さあ魂祭りだ 止まるのはちょい待って
Come on, it's a soul festival, wait a moment before stopping!
発見ののリズムを 最後まで
Keep that discovery rhythm going all the way to the end!
浴衣も忘れて跳ねるよ わっしょい！
Forgetting our yukatas, we're jumping around, Wasshoi!
もっともっと上がるよ 空に大きな夏の花
Rising higher and higher into the sky, a huge summer flower!
また飴ほおばる 溶けるよ一瞬
Munching on candy again, melting in an instant,
輝く時間も溶けてゆく 君との思い出
The sparkling moments melt away too, memories with you
溶けない 一生消えない 宝物
That won't melt, that will never disappear, my precious treasure!
祭だ祭だ祭だ わっしょい！
A festival, a festival, a festival, Wasshoi!
ちょい流れる光に 照らされて
Illuminated by the flowing lights,
全てが眩しい思い出は ちょいもっともっと
All those dazzling memories—even more, even more!
輝け君と 眺める夏の花
Shine brightly, the summer flowers we gaze at with you.
はい！君と眺める夏の花でした！ありがとうございました！
That was "Summer Flower We Gaze At With You"! Thank you!
いや、久しぶりに、ブルーム部員にね、ちょっと踊ったんで、
Man, it's been a while since I danced with the Bloom Club,
合ってたかなあ。
so I wonder if I got it right.
ああ、ちょっと不安だなあって思いながら踊りました。
While thinking, "Man, I'm kind of nervous," I danced.
そうして、ちょっとね、なんか変わったんですよ。何が変わったか分かるかい？
And you know, something changed. Do you know what changed?
さあ！ここ！さっきまで出てなかった このグラムを出してみました。どう？おしゃれじゃない？
That's right, right here! I tried putting out this gram that wasn't showing earlier. How is it? Isn't it stylish?
これもね、あの、この日のためにね、準備しました。
This too, you know, I prepared for this day.
ちなみに、その、この品物スピーカーとさっきのマイクと、このイヤホンマイク
By the way, the merchandise speaker, the mic from earlier, and this earphone mic—
全部ね、あの、祭りのパパで、ある、みなみらパパがね、
all of them, you know, were designed by Matsuri's papa,
デザインをしてくれたんですよ。ありがとうございます！
Minamira papa! Thank you very much!
それでは、えー、ちょっとここで告知タイムを…告知タイムをしたいと思います！
Now then, um, I'd like to squeeze in some notice time here—well, I'd like to do a notice time!
それでは、一つ目はもうみんな知ってると思うんですけど、こちら！
Now then, the first one is something everyone probably already knows, but here it is!
7月22日22時より、夏色祭りさん…さんって書いてある？ヤングドーナツセット発売決定です！
Starting July 22nd at 22:00, the Natsuiro Matsuri-san... It says "-san"? Young Donut set release is decided!
なんと数量限定8,888パチパチパチパチセット！限定なので、
It's a limited quantity of 8,888 clatter-clatter sets! Since it's limited,
え、この後、22時からね、急いで買ってくださいね！
um, please hurry and buy it starting at 22:00 tonight!
前回はちなみに、あの、5000個だったんですけど、5分で売り切れましたので、
By the way, last time, um, there were 5,000 units, but they sold out in 5 minutes,
まあでも今回は8,888個あるから、前回よりはゆっくり買えるんじゃないかなと思いますのでぜひぜひ手に入れてください。
so this time there are 8,888 units, so I think you can buy it a bit more leisurely than last time, please get your hands on it!
お願いします！キーホルダーとかも付きます。祭りが、こういうポーズにしたいっていうデザインも考えたのでぜひ、あの、買って下さい、手に入れてください。
Please! Keyholders and stuff will also be included. Matsuri thought of the design for wanting this kind of pose, so please buy it, get your hands on it!
はい！そしてそして！続いて、え、ナイトね、あの、まあよくあるやつですけども
Yes! And, and! Next, um, right, um, well, it's the usual kind of thing, but—
あ、やばい、後ろ向いて話してたのバレちゃった。
Ah, oops, you found out I was talking facing backward!
歩きながらしゃべってもばれないやって思って
I thought if I walked while talking, no one would notice.
こうやってしゃべってたらばれちゃった
So I talked like this and got caught.
はずかし あの、じゃ、あまよくある、こちらです、どうぞ！
How embarrassing. Um, well, as you often see, here it is, ta-da!
え、な、夏色まつり誕生日記念2021ということで、
Natsuiro Matsuri's Birthday Commemoration 2021...
え、誕生日を記念した抱き枕カバーとSNS風アクリルキーホルダーを販売したいと思います！いえい！
...we'll be selling a body pillow cover and an SNS keychain to commemorate my birthday! Yay!
で、全体は、こちら、どん！
And the whole thing is, here, ta-da!
全体を見せたい。
I want to show the whole thing.
あ、これですね、これ。えっと、抱き枕カバーが表と裏があります。また後で大きいの見せます。
Ah, this is it. The body pillow cover has a front and back. I'll show a bigger one later.
そして、あ、でかいのでた。これね。え、イラストはセラミック先生。あのよく、あ、でもコロナのは、あの、歌ってみたとか、おかゆの歌ってみた、まつりの歌ってみたも書いてるんですけど、あのいつもお世話になっております。
And, oh, the big one appeared. This is by Ceramic-sensei. They've drawn cover songs for Korone, Okayu, and me. Thank you always for your help.
すごくかわいいデザインになっております。表はなんだか誘う感じになっていて、裏これ見えるかな？ちょっと涙ぐんで、えーってなってる、ところなので、ぜひ手に入れてください！はい！
It has a very cute design. The front feels inviting, and the back—can you see? It's tearing up a bit, so please get it! Yes!
そして、そして、アクリルキーホルダーがこちら。
And next, the acrylic keychain is right here.
ですね。これは、見るみたいな感じになっております。これね、イルカなの、ここの上の部分かわいいっしょ。あのね、サカマタノヨテだったんだけど、ちょっとサカマタ人気すぎたからイルカになりました。お魚、イルカ、ま、誤答ですね。
It's designed to look like a post. The dolphin part on top is cute, right? It was supposed to be a killer whale, but they were too popular, so it became a dolphin. Close enough.
これを持ってね、お出かけすると、あの、ぱしゃって、こうスマホをかざして、アクリルキーホルダーをぱしゃって取るとですね、あの背景がスマホでデートしてる雰囲気にするんですよ。
If you go out with this and snap a pic holding up your smartphone, it makes it feel like you're on a date with the background.
で、ハッシュタグがあるんですけど、「夏色デート」というハッシュタグが書いてあると思うんで、これをね、つけてツイートすると、なんと！まつりから今日のデート楽しかったねってリプライが来ます！はい、送ります。あの、なんかアカウント鍵とかで見れない限りは送りたいと思いますので、ぜひ購入してツイートしちゃってください！はい！
There's a hashtag called \"Natsuiro Date\". If you tweet with it, a reply from me saying \"Today's date was fun!\" will come! I'll send it unless your account is locked. Please buy it and tweet!
そしてな、え、特典でボイスも付きますのでぜひな、ボイスも聞いてほしい。アクリルキーホルダーにぴったりのボイスと誕生日の、なんかいい感じのボイスが付きます！はい！
Also, a voice pack is included as a bonus! I want you to listen to it. A voice perfect for the keychain and a nice birthday voice will be included!
以上！ということでね、そんな感じのグッズは22時からかな？くらいから販売しますので、よろしくお願いします！
That's all! These goods will be on sale from around 22:00, so please check them out!
ということでそろそろもう50分になってね、時間が迫ってきているのですが、今日は楽しんでくれたかな？くれたかな？このあと22時30分より、あの、プレミアム公開で、あれが、あの動画が公開されるんですよ！何の動画かな？何の動画かな？楽しみだよね！その動画とは、
So it's almost 50 minutes and time is running short, but did you enjoy today? After this, at 22:30, a premiere of that video will be released! What video could it be? I'm excited! That video is...
ふう、ということで、えー、ライブはちょっと残念なんですけど、ここで終わり、ではなく、最後の最後に、
Phew, so, the live is a bit unfortunate, but it doesn't end here—at the very, very end,
歌うか、ちょっと。よいしょ。出番よ、マイク、あ、来た。最後の最後に聞いてほしい曲があります。22時半からは、今から歌う曲のショートバージョンが上がるから絶対見てくれよな！ということで、
shall I sing a bit? Upsy-daisy. It's your turn, mic—ah, it's here. There's a song I want you to hear at the very end. From 22:30, a short version will go up, so watch it!
最後までついてこいよ、まつりす！誕生日は最後まで終わらないぞ！それでは聞いてください！はいはい、ハイテンション！
Follow me all the way, Matsuris! Birthdays don't end until the very end! So listen up! Hi-Hi, High Tension!
パッと眩しい笑顔を咲かせ 歌え踊れ
Bloom a dazzling smile, sing and dance!
地球ごとレッツシュート！飛びきりの祭りはじめよう
Shoot the whole Earth! Let's start the ultimate festival!
ハイハイテンション！
Hi-Hi High Tension!
毎度マイペース
Always my own pace,
今こそセーフが主役 ゲンバフライト 次元も超えて
now is when safety is the protagonist, on-site flight, transcending dimensions too.
君と思い出重ねたら新しい未来へ
If I pile up memories with you, toward a new future.
あー見えなくたってなんでだろ伝わる 色とりどりの夢花火みたい打ち上がる ワクワク
Ah, even if I can't see, why is it? It gets across. Like colorful dream fireworks shooting up, exciting!
幕開け
The curtain opens...
Ah ah なんかイイ感じ
Ah ah, what a good feeling
青空 海どう?このロケーション
The blue sky, the sea, how do you like this location?
Ah ah マジでナイスバディ
Ah ah, you've got a really nice body
クモンベイビー DO THE ロコモーション
C'mon baby, do the locomotion
Ah ah ロコローション Ah ah ロコローション
Ah ah, loco lotion, ah ah, loco lotion...
カナラ ノータンキー
Very care-free
トロピカルバンジージャンプ!
Tropical bungy jump!
Hi! sweet 上がってけ
Hi! sweet, stand up
Yo! とことんホラHOT 差し込む太陽
Yo! Hey, you're really hot, I'll put you in the sun
「ハイテンション プリーズ」チラリズム ギリギリ
"High tension please" a just barely flickering rhythm
どう見せたい? SHOW TIME 招待
How do you want to enchant me? An invitation to show time
夏の大サマーセール!
The king of summer sail!
君は日々テルミー? 膨らむ妄想!?
Tell me about your days? A huge wild idea!?
真夏に始まるセレナーデ Oh Oh Oh
A serenade starting in midsummer, oh oh oh
Ah ah なんかイイ感じ
Ah ah, what a good feeling
青空 海どう?このロケーション
The blue sky, the sea, how do you like this location?
Ah ah マジでナイスバディ
Ah ah, you've got a really nice body
クモンベイビー DO THE ロコモーション
C'mon baby, do the locomotion
刺激たっぷりの君へエスコートしてぇ~!!
I want to escort you, who are full of excitement
ヒッチハイキング OK! バイブレーション
Hitchhiking is ok! Vibration
高まるアドレナリン 僕ドキドキ
Rising adrenaline flows through me
こめかみパンチング パンチラ パンパン
Punching your forehead, your underwear's showing, slap
ゴリゴリミュージック 車内はノリノリ
Music piece-by-piece, riding inside
さあさあ皆で声をそろえて歌いましょう
Alright, everyone sing together
刺激が欲しけりゃバカになれ Oh Oh Oh
If you want excitement, then get stupid, oh oh oh
Ah ah なんかイイ感じ
Ah ah, what a good feeling
青空 海どう?このロケーション
The blue sky, the sea, how do you like this location?
Ah ah マジでナイスバディ
Ah ah, you've got a really nice body
クモンベイビー DO THE ロコモーション
C'mon baby, do the locomotion
刺激たっぷりの君へエスコートしてぇ~!!
I want to escort you, who are full of excitement
Ah ah ロコローション Ah ah ロコローション
Ah ah, loco lotion, ah ah, loco lotion...
Ah ah なんかイイ感じ
Ah ah, what a good feeling
青空 海どう?このロケーション
The blue sky, the sea, how do you like this location?
Ah ah マジでナイスバディ
Ah ah, you've got a really nice body
クモンベイビー DO THE ロコモーション
C'mon baby, do the locomotion
Ah ah なんかイイ感じ
Ah ah, what a good feeling
ふたり包む空気 slow motion
The two of us are enveloped in the atmosphere, slow-motion
Ah ah マジでナイスバディ
Ah ah, you've got a really nice body
クモンベイビー お付き合い交渉
C'mon baby, let's talk about me escorting you
刺激たっぷりの穴へエスコートしてぇ~!!
I want to escort you to a hole that's full of excitement!!
Ah ah ロコローション Ah ah ロコローション
Ah ah, loco lotion, ah ah, loco lotion...
ロコローション
Loco lotion
Ah ah なんかイイ感じ
Ah ah, what a good feeling
青空 海どう?このロケーション
The blue sky, the sea, how do you like this location?
Ah ah マジでナイスバディ
Ah ah, you've got a really nice body
クモンベイビー DO THE ロコモーション
C'mon baby, do the locomotion
Ah ah ロコローション Ah ah ロコローション
Ah ah, loco lotion, ah ah, loco lotion...
カナラ ノータンキー
Very care-free
トロピカルバンジージャンプ!
Tropical bungy jump!
Hi! sweet 上がってけ
Hi! sweet, stand up
Yo! とことんホラHOT 差し込む太陽
Yo! Hey, you're really hot, I'll put you in the sun
「ハイテンション プリーズ」チラリズム ギリギリ
"High tension please" a just barely flickering rhythm
どう見せたい? SHOW TIME 招待
How do you want to enchant me? An invitation to show time
夏の大サマーセール!
The king of summer sail!
君は日々テルミー? 膨らむ妄想!?
Tell me about your days? A huge wild idea!?
真夏に始まるセレナーデ Oh Oh Oh
A serenade starting in midsummer, oh oh oh
Ah ah なんかイイ感じ
Ah ah, what a good feeling
青空 海どう?このロケーション
The blue sky, the sea, how do you like this location?
Ah ah マジでナイスバディ
Ah ah, you've got a really nice body
クモンベイビー DO THE ロコモーション
C'mon baby, do the locomotion
刺激たっぷりの君へエスコートしてぇ~!!
I want to escort you, who are full of excitement
ヒッチハイキング OK! バイブレーション
Hitchhiking is ok! Vibration
高まるアドレナリン 僕ドキドキ
Rising adrenaline flows through me
こめかみパンチング パンチラ パンパン
Punching your forehead, your underwear's showing, slap
ゴリゴリミュージック 車内はノリノリ
Music piece-by-piece, riding inside
さあさあ皆で声をそろえて歌いましょう
Alright, everyone sing together
刺激が欲しけりゃバカになれ Oh Oh Oh
If you want excitement, then get stupid, oh oh oh
Ah ah なんかイイ感じ
Ah ah, what a good feeling
青空 海どう?このロケーション
The blue sky, the sea, how do you like this location?
Ah ah マジでナイスバディ
Ah ah, you've got a really nice body
クモンベイビー DO THE ロコモーション
C'mon baby, do the locomotion
刺激たっぷりの君へエスコートしてぇ~!!
I want to escort you, who are full of excitement
Ah ah ロコローション Ah ah ロコローション
Ah ah, loco lotion, ah ah, loco lotion...
Ah ah なんかイイ感じ
Ah ah, what a good feeling
青空 海どう?このロケーション
The blue sky, the sea, how do you like this location?
Ah ah マジでナイスバディ
Ah ah, you've got a really nice body
クモンベイビー DO THE ロコモーション
C'mon baby, do the locomotion